Ethel Hopkins papers, 1933-1954
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Correspondence Files, 1933-1948
  - Subseries:Rodeo Files
    - Silver City (New Mexico). 1936-1938 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Soda Springs (Idaho). 1934-1937 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Sonora (California). 1935-1938 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Spokane (Washington). 1938-1939 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Springerville (Arizona). 1936-1937 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Stamford (Texas). 1934-1938 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Sun City (Kansas). 1938 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Sweetwater (Texas). 1936-1938 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Tahlequah (Oklahoma). 1946-1947 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Thermopolis (Wyoming). 1937-1938 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Victorville (California). 1936-1938 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Vinita (Oklahoma). 1937-1938 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Wahoo (Nebraska). 1935 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Wilcox (Arizona). 1936-1938 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Winnemucca (Nevada). 1936-1938 (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Wolf Point (Montana). 1935-1938 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Woodstown (New Jersey). 1935-1938 (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Woodward (Oklahoma). 1936-1938 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Subseries:Submission Files
    - Announcements--General. 1936-1948 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Announcements--Political Candidacy. 1938-1944 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Armstrong, Earl. 1946-1947 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Art Work--General. 1937-1948 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Chamberlain, Jim. 1947 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Corrections--General. 1936-1948 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Helfrich, DeVere. 1946-1947 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Henderson, Tex. 1947 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Magee, John A. 1945-1947 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Naegle, Marguerite. 1936 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Napoletano, Al. 1944-1946 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - News Items--General. 1937-1947 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Photographs--General. 1937-1947 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Poems--General. 1935-1947 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Ralston, Harry. 1937-1938 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Ricketts, Viva Leone. 1936-1937 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Rock, Florian. 1943-1946 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Rognan, Don. 1934-1936 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Roth, Henry. 1936 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Sandborgh, Bert. 1936-1937 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Shafer, Filomina. 1936-1938 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Shore, Hardy. 1944-1945 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Smith, Ida. 1946-1947 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Smith, "Plucky". 1937-1938 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Stories--General. 1936-1948 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Vaden, Clay. 1933-1937 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Williford, Opal. 1938 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Woods, Harry. 1935-1936 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Works Progress Administration. 1937-1938 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Wuori, Tyyne. 1937-1939 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Yokum, J. C. 1933-1936 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Young, Fred. 1936-1937 (Box 15, Folder 13)
- Photographs and Prints, 1936-1954
  2.5 Linear Feet (Approximately 1,890 items)
  The Photographs and Prints Series (1936-1954) is divided into three subseries.
  Subseries: Photographs (1936-1934) contains the bulk of the series, with the majority of the photographs depicting rodeo characters or scenes, including portraits, professional action photos, and candid shots. Mrs. Hopkins' scrapbooks have been disassembled but maintained in their original order with her inventories present. Of note are many signed portraits, inscribed to Ethel Hopkins. Most photographs are undated.
  Subseries: Prints (undated) contains a small number of pictorial prints generally reflecting rodeo or Western themes.
  Subseries: Oversized Materials (1939-1950) contains group and individual photographs of rodeo folk.
  - Subseries:Photographs
    - Animals. undated (Box 15, Folder 14-15)
    - Clowns. undated (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Cowboys. 1945-1953, undated (Box 15, Folder 17-18)
    - Families and Children. 1951, 1954, undated (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Groups. undated (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Hopkins, Ethel. undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Landscapes. undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous. undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Performers--General. undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Portraits. undated (Box 16, Folder 5-6)
    - Postcards. undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Rodeo Competition. 1952-1954 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Scrapbook I. undated (Box 16, Folder 9-10)
    - Scrapbook II. 1936-1946, undated (Box 16, Folder 11-12)
    - Scrapbook III. 1943-1946, undated (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Scrapbook IV. undated (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Scrapbook IV. undated (Box 17, Folder 1-11)
    - Trick Riders. undated (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Trick Ropers. 1948, 1953, undated (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Trophies. undated (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Subseries:Prints
    - General. undated (Box 17, Folder 15-16)
  - Subseries:Oversized Materials
    - International Rodeo Association Convention--Officers,Delegates, and Visitors. 1950 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Portraits. undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Portraits. 1938, 1940 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Rodeo Association of American Convention--Delegates and Visitors. 1939 (Box 18, Folder 4)